<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Modhuka Paranagama</title>
    <link>https://tillyshan.github.io/Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Modhuka Paranagama</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://tillyshan.github.io/Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Car Price Prediction</title>
      <link>https://tillyshan.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillyshan.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Develop an ML model to predict car prices based on available data and build a web application using flask where users can input data and receive predicted values. The dataset comprises a total of 19,237 records with 18 features. In order to assess the significance of each feature, exploratory data analysis (EDA) was conducted. Subsequently, feature engineering was performed, leading to the exploration and implementation of various machine learning models.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Cardiovascular Desease Detection</title>
      <link>https://tillyshan.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillyshan.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>This project involves creating a machine learning model to classify individuals for cardiovascular disease. Customizations for two distinct business requirements will be implemented. Additionally, a user-friendly web application using Streamlit will be developed, enabling users to input data and receive prompt results. The dataset comprises a total of 70,000 records with 13 distinct features. Exploratory analysis was conducted to identify important insights and patterns. General medical standards were considered in the decision-making process regarding data, such as outlier removal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 3: Revenue Insights Hospitality Domain</title>
      <link>https://tillyshan.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillyshan.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>AtliQ Grands owns multiple five-star hotels across India. They have been in the hospitality industry for the past 20 years. Due to strategic moves from other competitors and ineffective decision-making in management, AtliQ Grands are losing its market share and revenue in the luxury/business hotels category. Received dataset with dim and fact tables in the business. Understood requirements and identified key matrices needed for analysis. Assessed if the dataset provided could calculate the required key matrices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Employee Presence Data Analitics Project</title>
      <link>https://tillyshan.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tillyshan.github.io/Portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Engaged with HR stakeholders to understand their specific needs and requirements. Worked collaboratively with HR to identify the key metrics relevant to employee presence and performance. Metrics might include attendance rates, punctuality, leave balances, and any other factors important to HR decision-making. Examined the provided dataset, including dim and fact tables, to assess its suitability for calculating the identified key metrics. Checked data quality, completeness, and relevance to ensure it aligns with HR requirements.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
